

173 Francisco de Paula Otero St., 5003, Córdoba, Argentina

🛘 (+54) 351-505-6312 | 🔀 ROHAAN@gmail.com | 🖸 GonzaloUlla | 🛅 Gonzalo Ulla | 💆 @gonulla | 🐧 gonza.u

"Placed in between organizations and technology, I am committed and enthusiastic in what I do. Driven by great challenges and learning opportunities, I look forward to combining technical knowledge with interpersonal skills."

Summary₋

Cloud Software Engineer at McAfee. MS in Systems Engineering & BBA with a Major in Finance. MBA & MS in Software Engineering in progress. Information Systems Researcher at CIDS, UTN. Business-oriented Software Engineer specialized in Agile Methodologies and Cloud Technologies.

Work Experience _____

McAfee LLC Cordoba, Argentina

CLOUD SOFTWARE ENGINEER Mar. 2019 - PRESENT

- Currently performing as Scrum Master and developing Cloud-Native Microservices
- · Led Scrum Ceremonies and tracked progress in Jira for one Scrum Team. Worked with Stakeholders to refine the Backlog and plan Sprints
- Built multiple Microservices and Software Components using Java 8, Spring Framework/Boot & Python
- · Deployed and maintained cloud infrastructure using AWS, Docker, Kubernetes, TeamCity CI/CD, Ansible & Bash as DevOps technologies
- Developed a Streaming Platform with Apache Kafka, Beam & Flink as Data Engineering technologies
- · Solid experience with several tools and solutions such as Git, Grafana, Kibana, ElasticSearch & InfluxDB

CIDS, National Technological University

Cordoba, Argentina

Mar. 2019 - PRESENT

INFORMATION SYSTEMS RESEARCHER

- Researcher at CIDS Research Center of National Technological University, Cordoba Regional Faculty (UTN FRC)
- Current project: "Analysis Model to derive functional requirements by applying Business Patterns to a Conceptual Model"

McAfee LLC Cordoba, Argentina

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN Apr. 2018 - Feb. 2019

- · Involved with Cloud solutions, Java projects, DevOps and Performance testing activities, developing automation frameworks
- Performance testing tasks accomplished using Python, Docker, Grafana, ELK Stack and TICK Stack
- Solid experience with several GNU/Linux distributions

Education

National University of La Plata

La Plata, Argentina

M.S. IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

Apr. 2019 - Exp. Nov. 2020

• Currently studying at Computer Science Faculty of National University of La Plata

National University of Cordoba

Cordoba, Argentina

Apr. 2019 - Exp. Nov. 2020

• Got an Academic Merit Scholarship due to previous undergraduate performance

National Technological University

Cordoba, Argentina

M.S. IN SYSTEMS ENGINEERING

Jan. 2014 - Dec. 2018

• Standard bearer at UTN FRC. GPA: 9.84/10 (highest GPA award). Passed subjects: 42/42

National University of Cordoba

Cordoba, Argentina

LICENTIATE DEGREE IN BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION

Jan. 2014 - Dec. 2018

• Standard bearer at UNC FCE. GPA: 9.53/10 (highest GPA award). Passed subjects: 42/42

Skills

Programming Java, Python, Spring Framework/Boot, Hibernate, Django

DevOps AWS, Docker, Kubernetes, TeamCity CI/CD, CircleCI, Ansible, Bash scripting

Data Engineering Apache Kafka, Beam & Flink

Tools Jira, Git, Grafana, Kibana, ElasticSearch, InfluxDB, JMeter, YourKit

Languages English, Spanish

GONZALO ULLA · RÉSUMÉ **SEPTEMBER 13, 2021**

Certifications

Test of English as a Foreign Language (TOEFL), Score: 110. Educational Testing Service TOEFL iBT®

2013 First Certificate in English (FCE), Grade A, University of Cambridge ESOL Examinations

CABA, Argentina Cordoba, Argentina

Projects, Publications & Courses

6th National Congress of Computer Engineering - Information Systems (CoNallSI)

Mar del Plata, Argentina

AUTHOR OF: "HELPO: AN ONLINE PLATFORM FOR SOCIAL PURPOSES"

Nov. 2018

• M.S. in Systems Engineering, Final degree project, UTN FRC

• Winner of the award: "Best community-chosen project" (Córdoba, 2018)

Bachelor of Business Administration

Cordoba, Argentina

AUTHOR OF: "INVESTMENT PROJECT EVALUATION OF A TECHNOLOGICAL ENTREPRENEURSHIP FOR SOCIAL PURPOSES"

Nov. 2018

• Licentiate degree in Business Administration, Final degree work, UNC FCE

Introduction to Business Intelligence course

Cordoba, Argentina

DURATION: 24 HOURS, INFORMATION SYSTEMS ENGINEERING DEPARTMENT OF UTN FRC

Aug. 2018

• BI technologies: SSIS, SSAS, PowerBI, Kyubit

"Estrategias Cima S.A." enterprise

Cordoba, Argentina

AUTHOR OF A BUSINESS STRATEGIC CONSULTING PROJECT

May. 2018

· Final work of Strategic Management, B.B.A., UNC FCE

"Cattaneo Hnos. S.R.L." enterprise

Cordoba, Argentina

AUTHOR OF A BUSINESS CONSULTING PROJECT

Aug. 2017

• Final work of Administrative Systems and Procedures, B.B.A., UNC FCE

Web search engine using PageRank algorithm

Cordoba, Argentina

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

Jul. 2017

• Final work of Design of Query Languages, M.S. in Systems Engineering, UTN FRC

3rd Business Projects and Ideas Exhibition Day

Cordoba, Argentina

EXHIBITOR

Aug. 2015

• Final work of Management Principles, B.B.A., UNC FCE

Extracurricular Activity

Hogar Padre Lucchese

Villa Allende, Argentina

VOLUNTEER

Mar. 2014 - Dec. 2015

Additional Information

Travelling Passport, U.S. Visa and driving license